Coolidge Senior High School Oral History Project OHP028
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Coolidge Senior High School Oral History Project Collection
undated
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Drake, Ingrid
OHP028
0.25 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
Ingrid Drake, CGAP (Certified Government Auditing Professional), is a program analyst with the Office of District of Columbia Auditor (ODCA). Previously she was an investigator for the Washington-based nonprofit Project On Government Oversight (POGO); and was a writer, Pacifica Radio correspondent, and community educator living in Washington, DC. In 2007 at the time of gift, she was a local DC journalist, writing for several outlets: DC North, East of the River, Hill Rag, DC Radio Co-op, www.DCIndymedia.org, WPFW 89.3 FM - Pacifica Radio, and Free Speech Radio News. Contact info: IngridNatasha@yahoo.com.
Arrangement
This collection is housed in one box, 0.25 linear feet, and contains two series. The first series is organized alphabetically by last name of the first interviewee on the CD (some CDs contain multiple interviews) and contains 16 folders. The second series contains color 4"x6" photographs of the interviewees in two folders.
Scope and Contents
In 2007, Ingrid Drake coordinated the Coolidge Senior High School Oral History Project, interviewing 25 alumni, staff, teachers and then-current students of Calvin Coolidge Senior High School in Washington, DC. The project arose from Drake's professional relationship with Verna Avery-Brown; Drake was a volunteer at WPFW 89.3 FM - Pacific Radio, where Verna Avery-Brown was a news anchor. Avery-Brown is an alumna of Coolidge Senior High School. Coolidge has an active alumni association. Drake applied for and received a $5,000 grant from the DC Commission on the Arts and Humanities. With those funds, Drake obtained equipment and facilitated interviews between then-current students and alumni, teachers, staff and parents in school classrooms; produced a WPFW radio show of the final interviews; and bound copies of the interviews to give to the alumni. A copy of the final radio show and the interviews were burned to audio CDs and given to three institutions: the Calvin Coolidge Senior High School library, the Moorland-Spingarn Research Center at Howard University, and the Charles Sumner School Museum and Archives, all located in Washington, DC. This collection is comprised of 16 audio CDS (14 CDs of 24 interviews of 27 people, plus 2 CDS for the final radio show), and 26 color 4"x6" photographs of 25 of the 27 interviewees (includes one duplicate photo). The radio show contains snippets of interviews interwoven with popular commercially recorded music.
The Coolidge Senior High School Oral History Project interviews reflect the school's history of student political and social activism, demographic changes in the student body, and a chronicle of school spirit between the mid-1960s to 1997. The earliest alumni interviews are from the class of 1965; the latest from class of 1997. Missing are interviews with alumni who graduated during the 1980s and much of the 1990s. Included are stories of a student chapter of the Black Panther Party, a student march with a coffin to the White House during the Vietnam War, student pushes for creating black studies in high school, mention of the DC riots, historic DC events, student clubs, sports and extracurricular activities, popular music and dances, and the activism of the alumni association. Notable Coolidge alumni include Verna Avery-Brown, former Washington Bureau Chief of Pacifica Radio news in Washington, DC; Michael Blakey, biological anthropologist and director of the African Burial Ground Project in New York City; Ada Mitchell, physical educator teacher and coach at Coolidge Senior High School for 42 years; Philip PremDas, state director, GED administrator and chief examiner for the Office of the State Superintendent of Education (OSSE) in Washington, DC; and Davey Yarborough, internationally known saxophonist, recording artist, performer, bandleader, composer, arranger and educator, and creator of the internationally recognized jazz studies program and jazz orchestra at Duke Ellington School for the Arts in Washington, DC.
Interviewed are 27 people: Verna Avery-Brown, Vanilla Beane, Gregory Bell, Michael Blakey, Consuelo Ellis Brown, L. Nelson Burton, Christine Easterling, Kenneth Ellerbe, Terry Goings, Susan Gordon, Terri Jo Hayes, Jerome Johnson, Frank Jones III, Loretta Kelly, John Mercer, Ada Mitchell, Aric Moore, Donna Pixley, Philip PremDas, James Proctor, Shawn Ruffing, Harold Smith, Vincent Tate, Ray Weaver, Stephen Whitney, Sylvia Frazier Weathers (d. Aug. 21, 2010) and Davey Yarborough.
Oral History; Photographs
- Series 1: Oral Histories
  - Coolidge Oral History Project (Disc One), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Disc 1 of 2-disc set, compilation of oral histories of Coolidge Senior High School, Washington, DC.CD-R, 700MB, 80 minutes, Memorex. In plastic CD jewel case. Eleven tracks listed on inside cover. Notes include acknowledgments: Thanks to all the alumni who contributed their time and memories. Many thanks to Ms. Kelly her 11th grade and 12th grade classes. Terry Goings the PTSO, Frank Jones the Alumni Assn., L Nelson Burton, Ray Weaver, Alexander Cole, Eriqa Mason, Mario Horton, Shana Smith, Roshin Mathew, Hayden Wetzel of the Sumner School Archives, Selina Musuta and Radio Rootz, Ryme Katkhouda, the People's Media Center at Al-Fishawy Cafe, Matt Gilmore the Washingtoniana Collection, and WPFW Radio 89.3FM.
    - Introduction, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - John Mercer, Stephen Whitney, Philip Premdas, Connie Ellis Brown, Class of 1965, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Michael Blakey, Class of 1971, undated (Item 3)
      Track 3 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Verna Avery-Brown, Class of 1971, undated (Item 4)
      Track 4 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Davey Yarborough, Class of 1971, undated (Item 5)
      Track 5 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Susan Gordon, teacher, undated (Item 6)
      Track 6 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - James Proctor and Gregory Bell, Class of 1974, undated (Item 7)
      Track 7 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Sylvia Frazier Weathers, teacher, undated (Item 8)
      Track 8 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Frank Jones III, Class of 1975, undated (Item 9)
      Track 9 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Terry Goings, Class of 1977, undated (Item 10)
      Track 10 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Vincent Tate, Class of 1978, undated (Item 11)
      Track 11 of Disc 1 of Coolidge Oral History Project
  - Coolidge Oral History Project (Disc Two), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Disc 2 of 2-disc set, compilation of oral hstories of Coolidge Senior High School in Washington, DC. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 minutes. Memorex. In plastic CD jeewel case. Fourteen tracks listed on inside cover. Notes of acknowledgment: This project was made possible thru a grant from the DC Commission on the Arts and Humanities. For more information, contact Ingrid Drake, Project Coordinator, at theteachingreporter@yahoo.com or 202-577-3437.
    - Kenneth B. Ellerbe, Class of 1978, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Donna Pixley, Class of 1978, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Ada Mitchell, Class of 1967 and coach, undated (Item 3)
      Track 3 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Terri Jo Hayes, Class of 1979, undated (Item 4)
      Track 4 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Ray Weaver, Class of 1979, undated (Item 5)
      Track 5 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Aric Moore, Class of 1979, undated (Item 6)
      Track 6 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - L. Nelson Burton, Class of 1990, undated (Item 7)
      Track 7 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Christine D. Easterlling, staff, undated (Item 8)
      Track 8 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Shawn Ruffing, Class of 1997 staff, undated (Item 9)
      Track 9 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Jerome Johnson, parent, undated (Item 10)
      Track 10 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Students, Class of 2008, undated (Item 11)
      Track 11 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Loretta Kelly, teacher, undated (Item 12)
      Track 12 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Alumni Involvement, undated (Item 13)
      Track 13 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
    - Credits, undated (Item 14)
      Track 14 of Disc 2 of Coolidge Oral History Project
  - 1-Verna Avery-Brown 2-Susan Gordon Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Verna Avery-Brown, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Brown/Gordon interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
    - Susan Gordon, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Brown/Gordon interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Vanilla Beane 2 - Harold Smith Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Vanilla Beane, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Beane/Smith interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
    - Harold Smith, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Beane/Smith interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
  - Michael Blakey - 77:02 Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Entire CD is Michael Blakey interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Imation. In paper sleeve.
  - 1--L. Nelson Burton - 20:03; 2--Christine Easterling - 31:04 Coolidge Oral History, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - L. Nelson Burton - 20:03, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Burton/Easterling interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Imation. In paper sleeve.
    - Christine Easterling - 31:04, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Burton/Easterling interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Imation. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Terry Goings - 37:43 2 - Kenneth Ellerbe, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Terry Goings - 37:43, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Goings/Ellerbe interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Imation. In paper sleeve.
    - Kenneth Ellerbe - 28:37, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Goings/Ellerbe interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Imation. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Terri Jo Hayes 2-Jerome Johnson Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Terri Jo Hayes, Class of 1979, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Hayes/Johnson interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
    - Jerome Johnson, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Hayes/Johnson interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Frank Jones III 2-Loretta Kelly Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Frank Jones III, Class of 1975, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Jones/Kelly interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
    - Loretta Kelly, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Jones/Kelly interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Ada Mitchell 2-Aric Moore Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ada Mitchell, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Mitchell/Moore interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
    - Aric Moore, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Mitchell/Moore interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Donna Pixley 2-Shawn Ruffing 2-Vincent Tate Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Donna Pixley, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Pixley/Ruffing/Tate interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Memorex. In paper sleeve.
    - Shawn Ruffing, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Pixley/Ruffing/Tate interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Memorex. In paper sleeve.
    - Vincent Tate, undated (Item 3)
      Track 3 of Disc 1 of Pixley/Ruffing/Tate interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Memorex. In paper sleeve.
  - Phil PremDas, Stephen Whitney, John Mercer and Consuelo Ellis Brown - Part 1 - 44:26, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Disc 1 of 2 discs of PremDas/Whitney/Mercer/Brown interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Imation. In paper sleeve.
  - Phil PremDas, Stephen Whitney, John Mercer and Consuelo Ellis Brown Part 2 of Coolidge alumni interview, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Disc 2 of 2 discs of PremDas/Whitney/Mercer/Brown interview.. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
  - James Proctor Greg Bell Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - James Proctor, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Proctor/Bell interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
    - Greg Bell, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Proctor/Bell interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Staples. In paper sleeve.
  - 1-Sylvia Frazier Weathers 2-Ray Weaver Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Sylvia Frazier Weathers, undated (Item 1)
      Track 1 of Disc 1 of Weathers/Weaver interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Memorex. In paper sleeve.
    - Ray Weaver, undated (Item 2)
      Track 2 of Disc 1 of Weathers/Weaver interview. CD-R, 700 MB, 80 min. Memorex. In paper sleeve.
  - Davey Yarborough - 49:34 Coolidge Oral History Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Entire CD is Davey Yarborough interview. CD-R Audio, 80 min. Sony. In paper sleeve.
- Series 2: Photographs
  - Photos of Coolidge OHP, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Verna Avery-Brown, undated (Item 1)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Verna Avery-Brown, labeled in ink on back; Brown (left) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Vanilla Beane, undated (Item 2)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Vanilla Beane, labeled in ink on back; Beane (left) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Greg Bell, undated (Item 3)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Greg Bell, labeled in ink on back.
    - Michael Blakey, undated (Item 4)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Michael Blakey, labeled in ink on back; Blakey (right) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Consuelo Ellis Brown, undated (Item 5)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Consuelo (Connie) Ellis Brown, labeled in ink on back.
    - L. Nelson Burton, undated (Item 6)
      Color 4"x6" photo of L. Nelson Burton, labeled in ink on back; Burton (right) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Christine Easterling, undated (Item 7)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Christine Easterling, labeled in ink on back; Easterling (center, seated) is surrounded by unidentified students.
    - Kenneth Ellerbe, undated (Item 8)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Kenneth Ellerbe, labeled in ink on back.
    - Terry Goings, undated (Item 9)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Terry Goings, labeled in ink on back; Goings (right) is walking down a hall, being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Susan Gordon, undated (Item 10)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Susan Gordon, labeled in ink on back.
    - Terri Jo Hayes, undated (Item 11)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Terri Jo Hayes, labeled in ink on back. Hayes is displaying an old photograph of cheerleaders from Coolidge High School.
    - Jerome Johnson, undated (Item 12)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Jerome Johnson, labeled in ink on back.
    - Frank Jones III, undated (Item 13)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Frank Jones III, labeled in ink on back; Jones (right, with glasses atop head) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Loretta Kelly, undated (Item 14)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Loretta Kelly, labeled in ink on back.
  - Photos of Coolidge OHP, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - John Mercer, undated (Item 1)
      Color 4"x6" photo of John Mercer, labeled in ink on back. Mercer (right) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Ada Mitchell, undated (Item 2)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Ada Mitchell, labeled in ink on back. Mitchell (center, standing with hat on) is surrounded by unidentified students.
    - Ada Mitchell, undated (Item 3)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Ada Mitchell, labeled in pencil on back. Mitchell (center, standing with hat on) is surrounded by unidentified students.
    - Aric Moore, undated (Item 4)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Aric Moore, labeled in ink on back. Moore (seated, center, flipping through scrapbook) is surrounded by unidentified students.
    - James Proctor, undated (Item 5)
      Color 4"x6" photo of James Proctor, labeled in ink on back.
    - Phil PremDas and Stephen Whitney, undated (Item 6)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Philip PremDas (left) and Stephen Whitney (right), labeled in ink on back. Whitney (in blue shirt) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Shawn Ruffing, undated (Item 7)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Shawn Ruffing, labeled in ink on back.
    - Harold Smith, undated (Item 8)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Harold Smith, labeled in ink on back. Smith (right, seated) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Vincent Tate, undated (Item 9)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Vincent Tate, labeled in ink on back. Tate (back row, center, with gray beard) is surrounded by unidentified students.
    - Sylvia Frazier Weathers, undated (Item 10)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Sylvia Frazier Weathers, labeled in ink on back. Weathers (right) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Ray Weaver, undated (Item 11)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Ray Weaver, labeled in ink on back. Weaver (center, standing in back) is surrounded by unidentified students.
    - Phil PremDas and Stephen Whitney, undated (Item 12)
      Color photocopy of 4"x6" photo of Philip PremDas and Stephen Whitney, labeled in pencil. Whitney (seated, right, in blue shirt) is being interviewed by an unidentified student.
    - Davey Yarborough, undated (Item 13)
      Color 4"x6" photo of Davey Yarborough, labeled in ink. Yarborough is playing a clarinet.